That somebody that they've used Apache software within the last hour.
And they have they have because not only are particular projects
particularly widespread, but the spread of projects is enormous.
And so for instance, if they've used a credit card,
if they've used television, if they've used a web browser, they use the laptop.
It's almost certain that they've used some Apache software,
not knowing it, not necessarily seeing it.
But it's almost certainly there.
And it's unless you've been asleep for the last eight hours,
it's really, really hard to go in a modern technological sense,
more than just a short period of time without using some Apache software.
Why do we give it away? Because what we do.
because the impact of open source is that openness.
the ability for anyone to come and use and consume and contribute.
Hundreds and hundreds of years where knowledge was used to generate money.
And the only success factor in society is how much money is my company making.
I think the ASF has proven that even without making money,
we did have a humongous impact in the way which the world runs.
What would have defined success?
The project success is based on the people rather than the code.
And that's pretty much what comes about by the Apache way,
The community is far more important than the code.
The code will survive whether or not the community does.
But it won't get any better on being rich.
They won't go on to succeed unless there's a community that is supported.
One of the things we're seeing nowadays
is that the lessons learned inside of IT as far as how to create successful open source projects.
But most important, how to create successful open source communities,
of which the apache way is most probably the best example of
that is starting to make inroads in other areas.
This excessive open source is gonna expand beyond IT
is gonna expand beyond other software development in ecosystem.
We're seeing open source cities now where the ideas of how to engage the populace,
how to engage the citizens are using some of the tenants
and some of the ideals of the apache way
making sure that there is transparency in all the decision making processes of government.
I this is how you build software,
is by making sure that everyone involved both the people who are creating the software,
who are creating the software, creating the laws,
as well as the end users of the software and the citizens who were going to be abiding by the law.
Is everything open? Everything is being done, an open, public, and transparent manner.
So we're seeing a lot of the tenants of successful open source.
A lot of the means of the Apache way transcend the IT community
and make inroads into government, corporate entities, a heavy industry, manufacturing, machining.
And I think that's an incredible heritage for the movement we've created.
At the use cases that get me excited are the ones that are about trying to address
any one of those two hundred and sixty different sustainable development goals out there right
if we're going to have a carbon trading market
we're going to need a distributed ledger system to be able to do that on a global scale
if we're going to eliminate child labor in mines or on fishing boats or in other industries
it's going to be through technologies like this.
FIN act is a project that supports Micro finance institutions in giving out loans
and and tracking savings for the poorest of the poor.
So it's very rewarding to be able to make these services available to the poor.
Because if you don't have savings, if you don't have loans,
if you don't have remittances, that's money transfers
then you don't have contact the global economy and you can't profit
when your boat doesn't rise when everybody else's boat rises.
In the case of this project, you're connecting the empowerment
are the poorest of the poor with the empowerment of other software developers.
And you're doing both of them in the context of a community.
So it's really wonderful parallels between open source software and micro finance.
Being part of that. It just gives me a great feeling
that we've been able to change the world for the better
A lot of our software helps developing countries.
The great strides the world has made today in the last 20 years of globalization,
with the developing countries growing and advancing on providing  better living conditions
and better economic advancement for its populations
That's a result of the Free software movements.
And Apache had a big hand in that.
I feel very strongly.
The only thing that will save us as a species from our own internal greed
and hatred and the distance that we put between human hearts.
And I occasionally I'm chided because I am very sensitive person  and have thin skin.
And they say, you need thicker skin.
Now thicker skin puts more distance between human hearts.
It allows more space for not like me.
It allows more space for us versus them.
And that will be our undoing, not just as technologists but as a species.
And we are at a crucial point in our evolution, I believe,
where we need to start caring more about each other and less about profit.
And the Apache way voices one part of that,
I think in a very powerful way.
When we put community above code,
that gives us the opportunity to have a place
where people can be passionate about solving other people's problems.
That is one element of good empathy.