what we create runs everywhere it's
literally used everywhere in the world
today without the passion the internet
that we know today would not have
happened the best database the best
streaming framework we're creating
industry's programming for fat people
it's a great group of people it's
connecting people it's building bridges
people from China people from Europe it
doesn't matter what language you speak
where you come from
Apache is really good at bringing people
together and letting them work together
without companies getting in the way try
to learn something from everybody every
day inspiring it makes me want to be
better when working with people there
are so much better than yourself you
learn a lot community community in more
community people were so open and so
engaging and so excited to help don't be
afraid to give to share you would get
more out of it I've got more out of
Apache than I've ever given building
communities around people who are
passionate about solving problems create
incredibly passionate communities who
are then empowered to create incredibly
powerful software the software that
we've written how far it's gone and how
much it's used every day is staggering
I'm proud to be a part of an
organization that has changed the world
and I don't think many people understand
exactly how Apache has changed the world
it's impacted everyone when there's
something now you know people can touch
and you know act with their phones in
their car and you know you realize all
of us open-source software and it's like
wow okay this is something that's truly
changed the world
you know it's more than just technology
it's more than just coding it's bringing
new ideas new aspects there's so much
more we can do with the technology we
already have that is something that's
that's amazing
with the foundation that is something
it's so exciting and that is the thing
that really sort of keeps me interested
in and I'm passionate about
there's still so much work to do so like
I'm gonna be busy for a while I think
doing this kind of work and and I hope
many other people are too
the best software in the world I mean
that's the ASF
you